Finding Aid for Lexington General Store (Lexington, Mich.) records, 1851-1922
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lexington General Store (Lexington, Mich.) records 1851-1922
Lexington General Store (Lexington, Mich.)
11 microfilm rolls
28 linear feet
85257 BB 2; BB Microcopy
Lexington (Sanilac County, Mich.), general store, known variously as J. L. Woods & Co., Woods, Nims & Co., Nims, Tewksbury & Co., and A. W. Fenton & Co. Correspondence, financial journals, and letterpress books.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The provenance of the records is unclear.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
Chronology
1849 The Store was established by John L. Woods
1858 W.R. Nims was made partner and the firm takes the name of J.L. Woods & Co.
1863 Benjamin Farrington becomes the 2nd partner and the store becomes Woods, Nims & Co.
1865 Farrington retires and the name reverts to Woods & Nims
1873 Samuel C. Tewksbury purchases an interest and the firm is renamed Nims,Tewksbury & Co.
1880 Rudolph Papst buys out Nims and the firm is renamed Tewksbury, Papst & Co.
1884 Woods retires
1885 Papst retires and the name becomes S.C. Tewksbury & Co.
1898-1899 Tewksbury leaves Lexington and Albert E. Sleeper and Arthur Fenton become owners under the name of A.W. Fenton & Co.
19-- Fenton dies and Frank Wolfel becomes manager and is still holding that position in 1934.
The collection consists of original and microfilmed records. The series include: Correspondence; Letterpress books and other records; and Financial Journals.
Subjects:
General stores--Michigan--Lexington.; Lexington (Mich.); Sanilac County (Mich.)
- Correspondence
  - 1869-1870 1881-May 1886 (Box 1)
  - June 1886-December 1890 (Box 2)
  - 1891-1895 (Box 3)
  - 1896-1899 (Box 4)
  - Undated (Box 4)
- Letterpress books and other records
  - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 4)
  - Letterpress books December 1878-1906
    - December 1878-1885, 7 volumes (Box 4)
    - December 1885-December 1891, 11 volumes (Box 5)
    - December 1891-1906, 9 volumes (Box 6)
  - Lexington Dock Co., stockholder minutes 1866-1887 (Box 6)
  - Cash book, Schooner Patrick Henry 1862-1863, 1 volume (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous shipping records, Woods, Perry & Co. 1882, 1 volume (Box 7)
  - Wood's Mill Lumber Production records 1867-1868, 1 volume (Box 7)
- Financial Journals
  - Lexington General Store Journals
    (For the years 1851-October 16, 1905 the original volumes are available. For October 17, 1905-Ocotober 1922 the ledgers have been microfilmed and the original volumes discarded. The Lexington ledgers begin part way through microfilm roll 4.)
    - Journals May 1851-May 1854, 6 volumes (Box 7)
    - May 1854-May 1860, 6 volumes (Box 8)
    - September 1860-August 1862, 6 volumes (Box 9)
    - August 1862-July 1864, 6 volumes (Box 10)
    - July 1864-August 1866, 7 volumes (Box 11)
    - August 1866-March 1868, 6 volumes (Box 12)
    - April 1868-September 1869, 6 volumes (Box 13)
    - October 1869-February 1871, 5 volumes (Box 14)
    - February 1871-June 1872, 7 volumes (Box 15)
    - June 1872-December 1873, 5 volumes (Box 16)
    - December 1873-July 1875, 5 volumes (Box 17)
    - August 1875-March 1877, 5 volumes (Box 18)
    - April 1877-November 1878, 5 volumes (Box 19)
    - November 1878-July 1880, 5 volumes (Box 20)
    - July 1880-January 1882, 6 volumes (Box 21)
    - January 1882-February 1884, 7 volumes (Box 22)
    - February 1884-December 1885, 5 volumes (Box 23)
    - December 1885-July 1888, 7 volumes (Box 24)
    - July 1888-August 1891, 10 volumes (Box 25)
    - August 1891-March 1895, 9 volumes (Box 26)
    - March 1895-June 1901, 7 volumes (Box 27)
    - June1901-October 1905, 5 volumes (Box 28)
    - October 17, 1905-November 28, 1906 (Reel 4)
    - December 1, 1906-July 30, 1907 (Reel 5)
    - August 1, 1907-June 4, 1908 (Reel 5)
    - June 6, 1908-June 23, 1909 (Reel 5)
    - June 24, 1909-September 3, 1910 (Reel 6)
    - September 7, 1910-August 18, 1912 (Reel 6)
    - April 18, 1912-April 21, 1913 (Reel 6)
    - August 1913-January 1915 (Reel 7)
    - February 1915-December 1915 (Reel 7)
    - January 1916-October 1916 (Reel 8)
    - October 1916-August 1917 (Reel 8)
    - August 1917-August 1918 (Reel 8)
    - April 1918-July 1919 (Reel 9)
    - July 1919-May 1920 (Reel 9)
    - May 8, 1920-September 14, 1921 (Reel 10)
    - September 1921-March 1922 (Reel 11)
    - March 1922-October 1922 (Reel 11)
  - Other Companies
    [Microfilm)
    - J.L. Woods Ledger 1852-1856 (Reel 1)
    - J.L. Woods Ledger 1856-1861 (Reel 1)
    - J.L. Woods & Co. Ledger 1860-1873 (Reel 1)
    - Woods and Nims Ledger 1862-1873
      - 1862-1865 (Reel 2)
      - 1865-1869 (Reel 2)
      - 1869-1873 (Reel 2)
    - Nims, Tewksbury and Co. Ledger 1873-1876 (Reel 3)
    - Nims, Tewksbury and Co. Ledger 1877-1880 (Reel 3)
    - Tewksbury, Papst and Co. Ledger 1880-1885 (Reel 3)
    - J.C. Tewksbury & Co. Ledger 1885-1897 (Reel 4)
    - A.W. Fenton Ledger 1898-1927 (Reel 4)